healthfitnesskeeper.com 2018-10-13

# Privacy Policy | Health Fitness Keeper

## **Statement Of Confinement**

**Health Fitness Keeper**  is committed to protecting your privacy and any personal information we collect. We comply with the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth). This policy explains how we may collect, use, disclose and otherwise handle personal and sensitive information.

**Health Fitness Keeper**  is committed to safeguarding personal privacy. It recognises that individuals have a right to control how their personal information is collected and used. Providing personal information is an act of trust and it is taken seriously. Unless given consent to do otherwise,  **Health Fitness Keeper**  will only collect and use personal information as set out below.

For the purposes of this Privacy Policy personal information may mean some or all of the following: a member’s name, contact details, date of birth, emergency contact details, bank account and/or credit card details, student identification details, employment details, payment history and sensitive information.

## **Collecting Personal Information**

**Health Fitness Keeper**  will not collect or monitor any personal information about an individual without their consent.  The only personal information collected is what is provided voluntarily by a member or prospective member.

We collect personal information primarily to enable us to provide members with our services.  **Health Fitness Keeper**  may also use the information for marketing to you or for any other purpose permitted under the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth).

You don’t need to identify yourself when you deal with us ( e.g. to find out more about membership packages) however in certain situations we will only deal with individuals who have identified themselves to us.

When a membership or product is purchased personal information will be requested in order to provide the requested service or product, provide updated information, and advise of other  **Health Fitness Keeper**  products, which may be of interest.  You are not obligated to provide personal information however failure to do so may result in  **Health Fitness Keeper**  being unable to provide services or products to you.

Personal information is collected directly from members or potential future members when they personally complete and submit an application form to become a member of  **Health Fitness Keeper**. This can be done in person at one of our gymnasiums, on line via our website or on the phone via one of our Membership Consultants.

## **Collecting Sensitive Information**

For the purposes of this Privacy Policy sensitive information means the information a member has disclosed to us about their physical and mental health and well being.

Sensitive information will only ever be used for providing services to members. Such information will not be used or disclosed for any other purposes without consent, except in exceptional cases when disclosure may be required by law or is necessary to protect the rights or property of  **Health Fitness Keeper** ,  or any member of the public, or to lessen a serious threat to a person’s health or safety. For the purposes of this Privacy Policy sensitive information is a subset of personal information.

## **Use Of Tracking Technologies**

**Health Fitness Keeper**  uses tracking technologies such as cookies or web beacons to make use of the website and services as convenient as possible.  Cookies are pieces of information that a web site transfers to a computer’s hard disk for record keeping purposes.  Web Beacon is a technical method that sends information related to the access to websites, when you browse websites, open or preview an HTML-formatted email.  Most web browsers are set to accept tracking technologies such as cookies or web beacons.  These tracking technologies do not themselves personally identify users, although they do identify a user’s browser.  These tracking technologies allow **Health Fitness Keeper** to monitor the **Health Fitness Keeper** web site, and to record how many people are using the different parts of the site. It is possible to set the browser to refuse tracking technologies such as cookies or web beacons, however, this may limit the services provided by Health Fitness Keeper’s web site.

## **Using And Disclosing Your Personal Information**

Personal Information will be used for the following primary purpose:

  * – To fulfill obligations under a member’s membership agreement and/or any other contract between him/her and Health Fitness Keeper;
  * – To render services under a member’s membership agreement;
  * – To provide information about products, service and/or special offers to members;
  * – To obtain opinions or comments about products and/or services from members;
  * – To record statistical data for marketing analysis from members.

**Health Fitness Keeper** may employ other companies or service providers to assist us in providing our services, including (but not limited to) marketing, market research, mail-house services, hosting and product development services, analysis of member lists and/ or consulting services. These third parties may have access to personal information that is needed to perform their specific function. They cannot use that information for other purposes.

**Health Fitness Keeper** recognize the trust with which individuals provide personal information, and such information will not be used or disclosed for any other purposes without consent, except in exceptional cases when disclosure may be required by law or is necessary to protect the rights or property of Health Fitness Keeper, any Health Fitness Keeper group company, or any member of the public, or to lessen a serious threat to a person’s health or safety.

## **Contact By Health Fitness Keeper**

**Health Fitness Keeper** does not send advertising information without obtaining prior consent. If an individual receives communications from Health Fitness Keeper which they do not wish to receive, they may remove their name from the database by contacting Health Fitness Keeper at [info@healthfitnesskeeper.com](mailto:info@healthfitnesskeeper.com)

## **Individual’s Right Of Access**

Individuals have the right to review, amend or delete personal and/or sensitive Information that may be recorded on the **Health Fitness Keeper** database. Information may be reviewed, amended or deleted by completing the access request form at your home club’s reception, or by phoning 612-80113505.

A request may be made to delete personal and/or sensitive information, and all reasonable steps to delete the information will be made, except where it is required for legal reasons. Deletion of information may result in Health Fitness Keeper being unable to sell products directly and/or provide certain services including after sales services.

## **Storage And Security Of Personal And/Or Sensitive Information**

**Health Fitness Keeper**   takes all reasonable steps to keep secure personal information recorded and to keep this information accurate and up to date. The personal information is stored on secure servers if in digital format, or in locked areas if in hardcopy format: these repositories are protected in controlled facilities. In some cases these facilities may be in Amsterdam, England and the United States. Health Fitness Keeper employees and data processors are obliged to respect the confidentiality of any personal and/or sensitive information held by Health Fitness Keeper. Health Fitness Keeper only permits authorised personnel to access your information and information will only be disclosed to third parties where they have the appropriate authority. We destroy or de- identify personal information we no longer need, wherever possible.

## **Health Fitness Keeper And Links To Other Web Sites**

**Health Fitness Keeper** provides links to web sites outside of the Health Fitness Keeper site. These linked sites are not under the control of Health Fitness Keeper, and Health Fitness Keeper is not responsible for the conduct of companies linked to the Health Fitness Keeper web site, nor for the performance or otherwise of any content and/or software contained in such external websites.

## **Problems, Queries Or Complaints**

For further information regarding this Privacy Policy or to make a complaint about the steps taken by Health Fitness Keeper to protect your personal information or privacy, please contact Health Fitness Keeper’s Privacy Office by emailing [info@healthfitnesskeeper.com](mailto:info@healthfitnesskeeper.com)  or calling 612-80113505.  We will investigate any complaints received in writing and do our best to resolve them as soon as possible.

If you are not satisfied with the result of your complaint to us, you can refer your complaint to the:

Office of the Australian Information Commissioner

Phone 612-80113505.

**Health Fitness Keeper** reserves the right to review, amend, update and change this Privacy Policy from time to time to reflect its practices and obligations. Any changes will take effect when they are made or posted on our website.
